export const marketHolidays = {
  BSE: [
    {
      question: "How many trading holidays are there in 2024?",
      answer:
        "The Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) observes around 15 to 19 trading holidays in the year 2024. The exact number may vary depending on various factors, like special holidays, extraordinary events, etc.",
    },
    {
      question: "What are the regular trading hours in BSE?",
      answer: `Overall regular trading hours at BSE can be demonstrated as 
 <ul>
 <li>Pre-opening Session: <strong>09:00 a.m. to 09:15 a.m.</strong></li>
 <li>Normal Session: <strong>09:15 a.m. to 03:30 p.m.</strong></li>
 <li>Closing Session: <strong>03:30 p.m. to 04:00 p.m.</strong></li>
 </ul>`,
    },
    {
      question: "Does BSE operate on weekends in 2024?",
      answer:
        "No, BSE does not operate on weekends. It remains open for trading on weekdays, from Monday to Friday.",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Are there any partial trading days during the BSE holidays in 2024?",
      answer:
        "No, there are no partial trading days during the BSE holidays 2024. However, it may conduct short-duration special trading sessions on a selected holiday if required.",
    },
    {
      question: " Can I access market data on the BSE holidays 2024?",
      answer:
        "Yes, you can access real-time market data, news, and reports on BSE holidays through your broker’s platform or external data providers. However, it is important to note that you’ll not find any new data or trading activity on BSE holidays.",
    },
    {
      question: "What are BSE’s special trading sessions?",
      answer:
        "The special trading sessions of BSE refer to sessions conducted apart from the regular trading hours, like Muhurat trading sessions for an auspicious one-hour period on Diwali.",
    },
  ],
  MCX: [
    {
      question: "How many MCX holidays are there in 2024?",
      answer:
        "There are approximately 16 MCX holidays in the year 2024. However, the numbers may vary depending on various factors, like special holidays, extraordinary events, etc.",
    },
    {
      question: "Is MCX closed on Saturday and Sunday?",
      answer:
        "Yes, MCX remains closed on weekends (Saturday and Sunday). It operates only on weekdays (Monday to Friday) apart from declared holidays.",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the MCX market timing today?",
      answer:
        "The trading hours for MCX usually begin at 09:00 a.m. and conclude at 11:30 p.m., Monday to Friday.",
    },
    {
      question: "Which month has the maximum MCX holidays?",
      answer:
        "The March month of 2024 has the maximum number of MCX holidays. There are three holidays in March, including Mahashivratri, Holi, and Good Friday.",
    },
    {
      question: "Is MCX open on Diwali/Muhurat time?",
      answer:
        "Yes, MCX conducts the Muharat trading session on the day of Diwali. The timings of the trading sessions will be announced closer to the dates of Diwali.",
    },
    {
      question: "Are there any special trading hours on MCX holidays in 2024?",
      answer:
        "Yes, Muhurat trading sessions will be conducted as special trading hours on Diwali 2024. The session will be conducted for a short duration of 1 hour. These special sessions are announced by the stock exchanges themselves.",
    },
  ],
  NSE: [
    {
      question: "How many trading holidays are there in 2024?",
      answer:
        "The National Stock Exchange (NSE) observes around 16-18 trading holidays every year, including national holidays as well as a few exchange-specific holidays. The exact number may vary slightly each year.",
    },
    {
      question: "Are all trading segments affected by NSE holidays in 2024?",
      answer:
        "Yes, typically all the trading segments at NSE like equity, equity derivatives, currency derivatives, commodity derivatives, etc. remain closed for trading on the exchange-specified holidays.",
    },
    {
      question: "What are the regular trading hours in NSE?",
      answer: `The normal trading sessions at NSE are:
     <ul>
     <li>9:15 am to 3:30 pm for Equity and Equity Derivatives</li>
     <li>9:00 am to 5:00 pm for Currency Derivatives</li>
     <li>10:00 am to 11:30 pm for Commodity Derivatives</li>
     </ul>`,
    },
    {
      question: "Can I access market data on NSE holidays?",
      answer:
        "While trading is not allowed on NSE holidays, you can still access real-time market data, quotes, news and reports from a broker's platform or third-party data vendors. This enables analysis and strategy preparation for the next trading session.",
    },
    {
     question:"How are settlements handled around NSE holidays in 2024?",
     answer:"Trade settlements (pay-in and pay-out of funds/securities) are usually rescheduled to the next working day if the original settlement date falls on an NSE trading holiday. This prevents disruptions and ensures smooth clearing operations."
    },
    {
     question:"What are the special trading sessions of NSE?",
     answer:"Apart from the regular trading hours, NSE conducts special sessions like Muhurat Trading (for an auspicious 1-hour period) on Diwali day and a 90-minute session on Republic Day and Independence Day mornings. These allow trading activity during national holidays."
    },
    {
     question:"Do the NSE Holidays 2024 affect global markets?",
     answer:"No, NSE holidays have no direct impact on global equity markets like the US, UK, or other international exchanges as they operate independently based on their own calendars and regional holidays."
    },
    {
     question:"Is the NSE closed on national holidays in 2024?",
     answer:"Yes, the NSE remains closed for trading on all national holidays in India like Republic Day, Independence Day, Gandhi Jayanti, etc. However, it may conduct special trading sessions of shorter duration on a few select national holidays."
    }
  ],
};
